<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Json on GeekyRyan</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/json/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Json on GeekyRyan</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/json/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Powershell for Devops - Querying REST APIs with Powershell</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022-08-04-querying-rest-with-powershell/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022-08-04-querying-rest-with-powershell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This will be a short post on querying REST APIs with Powershell.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s hard to argue that REST APIs are the predominant technology for interacting&#xA;with networked services. They provide a gateway for interacting with a 3rd party (or self-hosted)&#xA;product without having to go through the exercise of a more complicated integration. REST APIs communicate&#xA;in a common format, typically JSON. However, most will allow us to choose the response format by specifying an&#xA;option in the &amp;lsquo;Accept&amp;rsquo; header.  Most languages provide a native method for interacting with&#xA;REST APIs. This objective for this post is to show you how simple this is with Powershell.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reading Json Files with Go</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022-07-21-reading-json-files-with-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022-07-21-reading-json-files-with-go/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;JSON is a widely used format for representing structured data. Developers like it because it is easy to read, most common languages have a library for interacting&#xA;with it, and most public APIs accept JSON in HTTP requests.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll look at parsing a JSON file using Go! We will be using the io/ioutil package to open a json file on local disk, and encoding/json to parse the&#xA;JSON data within the file into a memory structure.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
