<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>DevOps on GeekyRyan</title><link>https://rnemeth90.github.io/categories/devops/</link><description>Recent content in DevOps on GeekyRyan</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 17:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rnemeth90.github.io/categories/devops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Capturing Live Network Traffic from a Kubernetes Pod</title><link>https://rnemeth90.github.io/posts/2025-12-08-pcap-pod/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rnemeth90.github.io/posts/2025-12-08-pcap-pod/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="capturing-live-network-traffic-from-a-kubernetes-pod"&gt;
 Capturing Live Network Traffic from a Kubernetes Pod
 &lt;a class="heading-link" href="#capturing-live-network-traffic-from-a-kubernetes-pod"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fa-solid fa-link" aria-hidden="true" title="Link to heading"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
 &lt;span class="sr-only"&gt;Link to heading&lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Occasionally, you need to troubleshoot network behavior &lt;em&gt;inside&lt;/em&gt; a Kubernetes pod — maybe you&amp;rsquo;re chasing a DNS issue, testing service connectivity, or inspecting strange application traffic. &lt;code&gt;tcpdump&lt;/code&gt; is still one of the best tools for this, but pods are intentionally minimal, and most containers won&amp;rsquo;t have it installed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post shows a quick and dirty way to run a live packet capture &lt;strong&gt;from inside a pod&lt;/strong&gt;, without modifying your application container image.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Using try/catch/finally Blocks in PowerShell</title><link>https://rnemeth90.github.io/posts/2023-08-15-powershell-try-catch/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rnemeth90.github.io/posts/2023-08-15-powershell-try-catch/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Despite being a great language, PowerShell is not impervious to errors. Errors that occur within your code can stop it&amp;rsquo;s execution or even cause unexpected changes in the resources that your script is managing. Learning to handle these errors gracefully is the foundation of defensive coding. Today, we&amp;rsquo;ll take a quick look at how PowerShell handles errors with Try-Catch-Finally blocks. They allow you to gracefully handle errors and perform cleanup operations, ensuring that your script doesn&amp;rsquo;t crash when the unexpected occurs. We&amp;rsquo;ll then cover the differences in terminating and non-terminating errors and why you should take these into consideration when implementing error handling.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Golang: When Identical Strings are Not Equal</title><link>https://rnemeth90.github.io/posts/2023-01-24-golang-strings-not-equal/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rnemeth90.github.io/posts/2023-01-24-golang-strings-not-equal/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This will be a quick and dirty post, so please forgive any spelling/grammar mistakes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was writing a little CLI tool in Golang to track todo items. Just a dumb little app to help hone my skills a bit, but still something useful that serves a purpose to me. I don&amp;rsquo;t write a ton of code at work (mostly just scripting/pipelines when I do), so I&amp;rsquo;m constantly working on something like this in my spare time. Anyway, I was writing this app, got everything working like I wanted it to. I then wrote some of the tests and was iterating over them. I noticed the &lt;code&gt;ListTasks&lt;/code&gt; test was failing:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Building a Golang App with Github Actions</title><link>https://rnemeth90.github.io/posts/2022-12-24-gh-actions-copy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rnemeth90.github.io/posts/2022-12-24-gh-actions-copy/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll take a quick look at building a Golang app with Github actions. This process can be applied to just about any app
written in any language though. We&amp;rsquo;ll cover the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are github actions?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setting up the workflow to build, test, and deploy a binary&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Github Actions is a cross-platform CI/CD pipeline that allows you to build, test, package, and release your software. Actions can be triggered manually or based on events that happen within your Github repo. They are powerful and I suggest you read more at the &lt;a href="https://docs.github.com/en/actions/learn-github-actions/understanding-github-actions" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Official Docs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Chaining YAML Pipelines in Azure Devops</title><link>https://rnemeth90.github.io/posts/2022-11-03-chaining-yaml-pipelines-in-azure-devops-copy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rnemeth90.github.io/posts/2022-11-03-chaining-yaml-pipelines-in-azure-devops-copy/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll take a quick look at chaining two pipelines together in Azure Devops, so that the completion of one pipeline, triggers the other to run.
Microsoft documentation is leaps and bounds ahead of where it used to be. However, I still feel like there is a lot of room for improvement, as it took me a while to
figure this out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our two pipelines will exist in the same repository. We have a dependent-pipeline, that we only want to run once the source-pipeline is finished. This is useful if you have
some infrastructure you want to build, prior to deploying something to that infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Update Azure Devops SPN Secret</title><link>https://rnemeth90.github.io/posts/2022-09-12-update-azure-devops-spn-secret/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rnemeth90.github.io/posts/2022-09-12-update-azure-devops-spn-secret/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;If you need to update the secret for a service principal in Azure Devops, prior to it expiring, you may be surprised to find that this cannot be done via the Azure Portal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, I&amp;rsquo;ll show you two methods for updating a secret for a service principal prior to expiration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="update-the-secret-via-the-azure-devops-portal"&gt;
 Update the secret via the Azure Devops Portal:
 &lt;a class="heading-link" href="#update-the-secret-via-the-azure-devops-portal"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fa-solid fa-link" aria-hidden="true" title="Link to heading"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
 &lt;span class="sr-only"&gt;Link to heading&lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to &amp;ldquo;Service Connections&amp;rdquo; in the Azure Devops portal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find the SPN you want to update, then click &amp;ldquo;Manage Service Principal&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Then on the service principal page, click Certificates &amp;amp; Secrets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a &amp;ldquo;New Client Secret&amp;rdquo;, take note of the value&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Delete the &amp;lsquo;old&amp;rsquo; secret&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Return to the Service Connection in the Azure Devops portal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click Edit - click the verify button. It should tell you the client certificate has expired&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now you need to make an arbitrary change and save it. I just type a character in the optional description and save.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now edit again and click verify, it will now pick up the new client secret and all is happy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now remove whatever you added to the description.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>