<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Office365 on GeekyRyan</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/office365/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Office365 on GeekyRyan</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 16:31:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/office365/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Azure AD Sync &amp;#8211; Set-MsolDirSyncEnabled : You cannot turn off Active Directory synchronization.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2020-11-26-azure-ad-sync-set-msoldirsyncenabled/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 16:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2020-11-26-azure-ad-sync-set-msoldirsyncenabled/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently ran into a situation in my lab environment that required I resync all (2000+) user accounts to Azure AD. Though this sounds complex and daunting, its actually quite simple. T&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The basic steps involve disabling sync, and then removing the user objects. This can all be done with two PowerShell commands:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1) Set-MsolDirSyncEnabled -EnableDirSync $false&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-rGK18FXw7ns/X7_WthQR0CI/AAAAAAAAyCM/gg7MsY2fcVIcWMMbvxYzPpbpPyKwgHP8ACLcBGAsYHQ/image.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://rnemeth90.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/image.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2) Get-MsolUser -All | Remove-MsolUser -force&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-miyfN7OISGo/X7_WzDCc6iI/AAAAAAAAyCQ/PtHURTTVMQ4uypzO7L1UaLfyEs0fpYGdACLcBGAsYHQ/image.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://rnemeth90.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/image-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The account that you are currently running the commands as will not be removed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure AD Connect No-Start-Connection</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2018-07-26-azure-ad-connect-no-start-connection/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2018 12:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2018-07-26-azure-ad-connect-no-start-connection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This morning, I ran into an issue with Azure AD Connect that I had never seen before. I received an email alert from Azure AD stating that Password Synchronization was not working for my forest, and the suggested fix was to restart the ADSync service on the server. I restarted the service and then forced a sync to verify it was working.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After forcing the sync, I opened miisclient and noticed some strange errors. We sync multiple on-prem AD forests to Azure AD, and the status for one of them was “no-start-connection”. That error in itself does not seem significant to me. However, after clicking on the “failed-connection” link in the Connection Status pane, things became much more clear.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure AD Connect Health: Latest Data is not Available in Azure Portal</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2018-07-18-azure-ad-connect-health-latest-data-is/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 16:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2018-07-18-azure-ad-connect-health-latest-data-is/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently had to create a new Azure AD Connect server, and found that it was not able to report health status in the Azure Portal. After some troubleshooting/research, I was able to get the health status report working by registering the health agent on the server with Azure AD Health Services. Doing this involves running one PowerShell cmdlet on your AD Connect server and providing global administrator credentials.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://rnemeth90.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/2018-07-18_12h23_56.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://rnemeth90.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/2018-07-18_12h23_56.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Removing a Forest from Azure AD Connect</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2018-07-13-removing-forest-from-azure-ad-connect/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2018-07-13-removing-forest-from-azure-ad-connect/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In an organization with multiple Active Directory forests, you may want to sync objects from trusted forests. Adding trusted forests to Azure AD Sync is a simple process that I will likely cover in a future article. The focus of this post is the not-so-obvious process of removing a forest from Azure AD Connect. This can be a daunting and somewhat scary thing to do. Not fully understanding the process or having someone to guide you can leave you with thoughts like “what happens when I remove the forest from Azure AD Sync? Do on-premises objects get deleted? Are cloud objects deleted?”. I will try to answer these questions to the best of my ability and hopefully make the process simple and stress-free for you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exchange 2016 Hybrid Deploy Check: Username or Password Invalid</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2017-11-07-exchange-2016-hybrid-deploy-check-username-or-password-invalid/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2017 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2017-11-07-exchange-2016-hybrid-deploy-check-username-or-password-invalid/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;These days, it seems every Microsoft product comes with its own unique set of head scratchers. Microsoft Exchange Server is no exception to this. I was installing Exchange 2016 earlier today, to be used as a hybrid configuration server for Office 365 (no local mailboxes). I downloaded the self depackaging executable from Microsoft, and attempted to install it. If you currently have a hybrid configuration (which we did, with Exchange 2010), the Exchange 2016 installer will detect this and run some tests to verify that the Office 365 tenant is ready for Exchange 2016 (more info here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://technet.microsoft.com/en-us/library/ms.exch.setup.hybridconfigurationstatuspage%28v=exchg.160%29.aspx&#34;&gt;https://technet.microsoft.com/en-us/library/ms.exch.setup.hybridconfigurationstatuspage(v=exchg.160).aspx&lt;/a&gt;). You’ll be prompted for Office 365 credentials (the user must have the Organization Management role). Seems simple enough, right? Wrong.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Script: BulkAdd-SpamFilterWhitelist.ps1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2017-06-26-new-script-bulkadd-spamfilterwhitelist/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2017 22:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2017-06-26-new-script-bulkadd-spamfilterwhitelist/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This script is capable of adding a list of domains to an Exchange Online Spam Filter policy. It can be downloaded from TechNet or Github.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rnemeth90/PowerShell/blob/master/BulkAdd-SpamFilterWhitelist.ps1&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gallery.technet.microsoft.com/BulkAdd-SpamFilterWhitelist-2d2b596a&#34;&gt;TechNet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Permanently Remove Office 365 Users</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2017-06-20-how-to-permanently-remove-office-365-users/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2017 18:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2017-06-20-how-to-permanently-remove-office-365-users/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After deleting a user in Office 365, their account is moved to a ‘recycle bin’ for 30 days. This allows the user account to be easily recovered. This can often cause issues when attempting to recreate a mailbox while a hybrid configuration is in place.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To permanently delete the user within Office 365, first delete the user in the Office 365 Admin Portal or using Powershell. Then, connect to your Azure Active Directory environment with Powershell using the “Connect-MsolService” cmdlet.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Script for Setting the License for Multiple Office 365 User Accounts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2016-04-11-script-for-setting-the-license-for-multiple-office-365-user-accounts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2016 01:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2016-04-11-script-for-setting-the-license-for-multiple-office-365-user-accounts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A script for setting the Office 365 license for multiple users. Requires a CSV file named users.csv. This file must in the same directory as the script. The CSV file must contain three columns. The title of the columns should be UPN, UsageLocation, and SKU.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/open?id=0B2K6VOnt6zeXZ2Z6OFZhZVoyenc&#34;&gt;BulkSet-MsolUserLicense.ps1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure AD Connect Password Sync &amp;#8211; Disabled and Grayed Out</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2015-10-15-azure-ad-connect-password-sync-disabled/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2015 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2015-10-15-azure-ad-connect-password-sync-disabled/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ran into a problem earlier with the new Azure AD Connect Wizard. We had configured the wizard and synced around 500 AD accounts. However, password sync was not working. I opened the wizard to confirm the configuration and found that “Password Hash Synchronization” was disabled. It was greyed out and could not be enabled.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://rnemeth90.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/2015-10-15_08h43_18.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://rnemeth90.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/2015-10-15_08h43_18.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I called Microsoft and worked for a couple hours with a technician to resolve the issue. Thought I should post the resolution here in case anyone else encounters this.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Error When Reinstalling DirSync</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2015-08-13-error-when-reinstalling-dirsync/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2015 18:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2015-08-13-error-when-reinstalling-dirsync/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today is just not my day! After a failed attempt at installing/configuring DirSync, I removed it and tried to install and configure it again. This time did not prove any more successful. I was getting this error midway through the install process:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://geekyryan.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/1.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://geekyryan.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was able to figure this out after a little while and wanted to sure what I learned. If you are seeing this error message after removing DirSync and trying to reinstall, here’s what you need to do:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
