<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Web Development on GeekyRyan</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/web-development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Web Development on GeekyRyan</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/web-development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mounting Multiple Kubernetes Secrets into One Directory</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-06-29-mount-multiple-kubernetes-secrets-into-one-directory/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-06-29-mount-multiple-kubernetes-secrets-into-one-directory/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Combining multiple Kubernetes secrets into a single directory can streamline secret management in your applications. This guide walks you through the process of achieving this in Kubernetes, ensuring efficient and organized secret management.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;creating-secrets&#34;&gt;Creating Secrets&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First, create your secrets using the &lt;code&gt;kubectl create secret&lt;/code&gt; command:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;kubectl create secret generic secret-one --from-literal=key1=value1&#xA;kubectl create secret generic secret-two --from-literal=key2=value2&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Each secret can contain multiple key-value pairs, and you can add more secrets as needed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Detecting MIME Types in Go</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-03-27-golang-detect-file-type/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-03-27-golang-detect-file-type/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Knowing the type of a file you&amp;rsquo;re working with is not just a matter of curiosity — it&amp;rsquo;s often a necessity. This is especially true when you&amp;rsquo;re deciding whether or not a particular operation can be carried out on that file. Go, with its comprehensive standard library, offers a straightforward approach to identifying a file&amp;rsquo;s MIME type, ensuring that developers have the tools they need to make informed decisions about file manipulation. You may expect to find this functionality in the &lt;code&gt;file&lt;/code&gt; package, but you&amp;rsquo;d be wrong! Read on&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Validating URLs with Go</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-12-12-golang-url-validation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-12-12-golang-url-validation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll take a quick look at URL validation using Golang. It&amp;rsquo;s common to implement URL validation as a task within a HTTP request pipeline, typically as middleware. There are many different definitions of &amp;ldquo;validation&amp;rdquo;. For the purpose of this article, we will simply validate that a URL conforms to a particular text pattern.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I often see people (mistakenly) use URL and URI interchangeably. URL is actually is a sub-type of URI. A URL is a reference to a web resource, typically seen as a web address (e.g. &lt;a href=&#34;https://golang.org/project/%29&#34;&gt;https://golang.org/project/)&lt;/a&gt;. A URI, on the other hand, can be used to identify any type of resource, not just those on the internet.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
