<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Sre on GeekyRyan</title><link>https://rnemeth90.github.io/tags/sre/</link><description>Recent content in Sre on GeekyRyan</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rnemeth90.github.io/tags/sre/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Kubernetes Health Probing in Dotnet Console Apps</title><link>https://rnemeth90.github.io/posts/2024-12-05-dotnet-console-app-health-probe/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rnemeth90.github.io/posts/2024-12-05-dotnet-console-app-health-probe/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="introduction"&gt;
 Introduction
 &lt;a class="heading-link" href="#introduction"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fa-solid fa-link" aria-hidden="true" title="Link to heading"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
 &lt;span class="sr-only"&gt;Link to heading&lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post covers a simple and efficient solution for implementing liveness probes in pods running console applications (think background services or utility DaemonSets). A common question I see in Kubernetes forums is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;“How do I use health probes with console apps?”
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The typical responses often suggest:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sidecar Container with HTTP Server: Requires coding the server, building a sidecar container, and managing additional infrastructure. While effective, this can be overkill for lightweight applications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exec Probes with Shell Scripts: Feels hacky and can waste resources, depending on what the script does.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pods are meant to be lightweight, and both solutions can deviate from that principle.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Handling Graceful Shutdown in a .NET App Hosted in Kubernetes</title><link>https://rnemeth90.github.io/posts/2022-12-28-graceful-shutdown-in-kubernetes-dotnet-pod/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rnemeth90.github.io/posts/2022-12-28-graceful-shutdown-in-kubernetes-dotnet-pod/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I was recently involved with troubleshooting some API&amp;rsquo;s hosted in Kubernetes throwing http/502&amp;rsquo;s. This was incredibly difficult to diagnose because it seemingly happened at random, and I had never encountered anything like this. Being that I had never dealt with this in the past, and I (nor my team) was able to figure it out within a reasonable amount of time, I turned to google. My searches resulted in various blogs and SO posts of other people experiencing similar issues, but none of their resolutions worked for us. It was actually a combination of these blogs (and the resolutions posted) that ended up resolving our issue.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>