<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>WSUS on GeekyRyan</title>
    <link>https://rnemeth90.github.io/tags/wsus/</link>
    <description>Recent content in WSUS on GeekyRyan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 15:13:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rnemeth90.github.io/tags/wsus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>WSUS: Update Files Not Downloading (Content File Download Failed)</title>
      <link>https://rnemeth90.github.io/posts/2016-11-18-wsus-update-files-not-downloading/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 15:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rnemeth90.github.io/posts/2016-11-18-wsus-update-files-not-downloading/</guid>
      <description>This article will discuss an issue regarding WSUS failing to download updates from Microsoft Update servers. You may notice that the home page of your WSUS console states that it has downloaded 0MB of updates:

You may also see this event (or similar) in the Event Log.

This problem is caused by not specifying a valid path when assigning the WSUS content drive when first installing the role. The first time you load the WSUS console after installing the role, you will be prompted to specify the path to store Windows Update files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WSUS: An error occurred trying to connect the WSUS server</title>
      <link>https://rnemeth90.github.io/posts/2016-11-10-wsus-an-error-occurred-trying-to-connect-the-wsus-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2016 15:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rnemeth90.github.io/posts/2016-11-10-wsus-an-error-occurred-trying-to-connect-the-wsus-server/</guid>
      <description>Ran into this error message when configuring a new WSUS server:

Restarted the WSUS, WID, and IIS services to no avail. I even rebooted the server. The WSUS console would work for a short period of time, and then would randomly stop working.
I found that the WSUS app pool in IIS was being disabled anytime new clients connected to the server. I believe this was because the app pool was running out of usable memory.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
