<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>WSUS on GeekyRyan</title><link>https://rnemeth90.github.io/tags/wsus/</link><description>GeekyRyan (WSUS)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 15:13:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rnemeth90.github.io/tags/wsus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>WSUS: Update Files Not Downloading (Content File Download Failed)</title><link>https://rnemeth90.github.io/posts/2016-11-18-wsus-update-files-not-downloading/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 15:13:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rnemeth90.github.io/posts/2016-11-18-wsus-update-files-not-downloading/</guid><description>&lt;p>This article will discuss an issue regarding WSUS failing to download updates from Microsoft Update servers. You may notice that the home page of your WSUS console states that it has downloaded 0MB of updates:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://rnemeth90.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/2016-11-18_10h02_21.png">&lt;img src="https://rnemeth90.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/2016-11-18_10h02_21.png" alt="">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You may also see this event (or similar) in the Event Log.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://rnemeth90.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/2016-11-15_16h39_32.png">&lt;img src="https://rnemeth90.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/2016-11-15_16h39_32.png" alt="">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This problem is caused by not specifying a valid path when assigning the WSUS content drive when first installing the role. The first time you load the WSUS console after installing the role, you will be prompted to specify the path to store Windows Update files. WSUS does not like to have its content directory be the root of a partition. For example, if I were to specify “e:” as the path for the Windows Update content, the wizard would give you an error message stating that the path is not valid. However, it doesn’t prompt you to re-enter the path if you click close. The WSUS console opens immediately after and that invalid path is where WSUS will try to store your update files. This is and has been a known bug for a while and needs to be addressed by Microsoft. Evidence of the invalid path can be found in the registry under:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>HKLMSoftwareMicrosoftUpdate ServicesServerSetupContentDir&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://rnemeth90.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/2016-11-15_16h39_44.png">&lt;img src="https://rnemeth90.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/2016-11-15_16h39_44.png" alt="">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you come across this problem, you can change the ContentDir above to a valid path. Keep in mind that it cannot be the root of a partition. You need to specify a drive letter with a subfolder (eg: e:wsus).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://rnemeth90.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/2016-12-21_14h54_54.png">&lt;img src="https://rnemeth90.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/2016-12-21_14h54_54.png" alt="">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The other option is to reinstall the WSUS role. If you remove the role, the WID database is not removed, unless you remove that role as well (or manually delete the database). This means that when you reinstall the WSUS role, it will be able to use that same database and any clients that have contacted the WSUS server will immediately show up in the console. The same is true for update metadata. The new WSUS installation will still have the same approvals, denials, etc. as the old installation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Regardless of what option you choose, I suggest rebooting the server after you make the changes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>WSUS: An error occurred trying to connect the WSUS server</title><link>https://rnemeth90.github.io/posts/2016-11-10-wsus-an-error-occurred-trying-to-connect-the-wsus-server/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2016 15:18:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rnemeth90.github.io/posts/2016-11-10-wsus-an-error-occurred-trying-to-connect-the-wsus-server/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ran into this error message when configuring a new WSUS server:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://rnemeth90.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/2016-12-21_14h56_00.png">&lt;img src="https://rnemeth90.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/2016-12-21_14h56_00.png" alt="">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Restarted the WSUS, WID, and IIS services to no avail. I even rebooted the server. The WSUS console would work for a short period of time, and then would randomly stop working.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I found that the WSUS app pool in IIS was being disabled anytime new clients connected to the server. I believe this was because the app pool was running out of usable memory.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://rnemeth90.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/2016-11-09_21h28_56.png">&lt;img src="https://rnemeth90.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/2016-11-09_21h28_56.png" alt="">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can manually start the app pool in IIS, but it will continue to crash.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://rnemeth90.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/2016-12-21_14h56_48.png">&lt;img src="https://rnemeth90.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/2016-12-21_14h56_48.png" alt="">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The solution for me was to increase the memory limit available for the application pool:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://rnemeth90.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/2016-12-21_14h57_38.png">&lt;img src="https://rnemeth90.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/2016-12-21_14h57_38.png" alt="">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By default it is only configured to use just under 2 GBs. I reconfigured it to use up to 4 GB and the WSUS console has not crashed since. After re-configuring the memory for the application pool, run an IIS reset or reboot the server.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://rnemeth90.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/2016-11-09_21h31_40.png">&lt;img src="https://rnemeth90.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/2016-11-09_21h31_40.png" alt="">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>UPDATE: Setting the Private Memory Limit to “0” will allow the application pool to use whatever amount of memory it needs.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>