<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>C# on GeekyRyan</title><link>https://rnemeth90.github.io/tags/c%23/</link><description>Recent content in C# on GeekyRyan</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rnemeth90.github.io/tags/c%23/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Handling Graceful Shutdown in a .NET App Hosted in Kubernetes</title><link>https://rnemeth90.github.io/posts/2022-12-28-graceful-shutdown-in-kubernetes-dotnet-pod/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rnemeth90.github.io/posts/2022-12-28-graceful-shutdown-in-kubernetes-dotnet-pod/</guid><description>&lt;p>I was recently involved with troubleshooting some API&amp;rsquo;s hosted in Kubernetes throwing http/502&amp;rsquo;s. This was incredibly difficult to diagnose because it seemingly happened at random, and I had never encountered anything like this. Being that I had never dealt with this in the past, and I (nor my team) was able to figure it out within a reasonable amount of time, I turned to google. My searches resulted in various blogs and SO posts of other people experiencing similar issues, but none of their resolutions worked for us. It was actually a combination of these blogs (and the resolutions posted) that ended up resolving our issue.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>EF Core &amp;#8211; Unable to create an object of type DbContext</title><link>https://rnemeth90.github.io/posts/2022-06-12-ef-core-unable-to-create-an-object-of-type-dbcontext/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 13:58:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rnemeth90.github.io/posts/2022-06-12-ef-core-unable-to-create-an-object-of-type-dbcontext/</guid><description>&lt;p>This problem has bitten me more than once, and I can never remember how to fix it. So, why not write a blog post about it!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When running EF Core migrations in a solution, you may come across this error:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://rnemeth90.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/image-1-1024x142.png" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are several apparent causes. However, in my case (every time I have seen this), it has been caused by having multiple startup projects selected in Visual Studio.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To fix this, simply open your Solution properties and set the startup project to ‘Current Selection’.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>