<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Vmware on GeekyRyan</title><link>https://rnemeth90.github.io/tags/vmware/</link><description>Recent content in Vmware on GeekyRyan</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 01:22:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rnemeth90.github.io/tags/vmware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Reset GRUB/root Password for vCenter/PSC Appliance</title><link>https://rnemeth90.github.io/posts/2020-10-31-reset-grubroot-password-for-vcenterpsc/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 01:22:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rnemeth90.github.io/posts/2020-10-31-reset-grubroot-password-for-vcenterpsc/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In Redhat/Fedora/Cent, GRUB can be protected by running the grub-md5-crypt command and pasting the outputted password hash into the grub.conf file. vSphere 6.0 password protects grub by default. If you change the root password in the VAMI, the GRUB password is changed to match. If you do not change the root password, the GRUB password is “vmware”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To reset the GRUB password, we need to boot into a Cent or Redhat live CD. The ISO can be obtained here: &lt;a href="https://www.centos.org/download/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;https://www.centos.org/download/&lt;/a&gt;. Its best to upload the ISO to a datastore that the appliance has access to.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Could not connect to VMware Directory Service via LDAP when Deploying New vCenter Appliance</title><link>https://rnemeth90.github.io/posts/2020-10-28-could-not-connect-to-vmware-directory/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 13:51:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rnemeth90.github.io/posts/2020-10-28-could-not-connect-to-vmware-directory/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Problem:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deploying a brand new vCSA 6.7 appliance results in the following error during the second stage of the deployment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://rnemeth90.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/2020-10-28_07h29_02.png" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;&lt;img src="https://rnemeth90.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/2020-10-28_07h29_02.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="text-align: left;"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Solution:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This problem is almost always caused by DNS resolution. Once you create the appropriate A and PTR record for your appliance on a LOCAL DNS server, you should be to successfully complete the deployment. Local DNS resolution is required, you cannot use a public DNS server while installing vCenter. For example, 8.8.8.8 will not work.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Azure Site Recovery &amp;#8211; VMware-to-Azure: Wrong IP address discovered for VM</title><link>https://rnemeth90.github.io/posts/2018-08-21-azure-site-recovery-vmware-to-azure/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 17:26:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rnemeth90.github.io/posts/2018-08-21-azure-site-recovery-vmware-to-azure/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;When replicating virtual machines from VMware to Azure using Site Recovery, you may encounter an issue where the Configuration server discovers the wrong IP address for a VM. This can be caused by stale entries within the infrastructurevms MySQL table that is used by ASR to track VM attributes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To resolve this issue, you first need to disable replication for the VM in the Azure Portal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://rnemeth90.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/2018-08-21_13h20_26.png" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;&lt;img src="https://rnemeth90.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/2018-08-21_13h20_26.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, login to your ASR Configuration Server and open a CMD prompt as administrator. Browse to the bin directory for your ASR installation. For example, in my case ASR is installed on the E: partition under the following directory:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Remove Stubborn PSC or vCenter Appliance from an SSO Domain</title><link>https://rnemeth90.github.io/posts/2017-11-08-remove-stubborn-psc-or-vcenter/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2017 07:56:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rnemeth90.github.io/posts/2017-11-08-remove-stubborn-psc-or-vcenter/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;While attempting to decommission one of our vCenter sites, I ran into an issue removing one of the PSCs. This site consisted of two PSCs and one vCenter appliance. I removed the first PSC from the SSO domain successfully, and then removed the vCenter appliance. Things became a little tricky during the removal of the final PSC. This PSC did not get removed even after running the cmsso-util command. This article will detail the steps I took in decommissioning the site, as well as removing the stubborn PSC.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Running vSphere in VMware Workstation 12</title><link>https://rnemeth90.github.io/posts/2017-05-29-running-vsphere-in-vmware-workstation-12/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 01:09:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rnemeth90.github.io/posts/2017-05-29-running-vsphere-in-vmware-workstation-12/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In this post I’ll be walking through how to run a vSphere lab in VMware Workstation. I recently decided to obtain VCP6-DCV. Rather than driving up my electric bill like I’ve done in the past using physical servers, I’m attempting to run the entire lab on my workstation and a Synology NAS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’ve ever installed ESXi, installing it in Workstation will be a familiar process for you. VMware tools is included in the installation disc, which makes installing ESXi in Workstation dramatically easier than it used to be. . The process is very simple, so I won’t be going through those steps here unless someone asks me to in the comments. I also will not be going through the process of installing Windows Server or configuring a domain controller/DNS/DHCP, as I am sure you have done so in the past if you are reading this.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>